Good Morning!
I'm Manolo and I'm going to show you what
I have in my backpack, what are the things that
I brought for the tournament here in
Asturias, for the Spanish Open.
Let's go!
To start with the putters, I have the putters
that I use for putting. I have two identical ones,
two deputies. Deputy in the classic soft (plastic).
The Deputy is a disc that I like it a lot.
I got my first Deputy once at the Trilogy
Challenge and I was so cool that I said
"Oh, my God! This is so cool!" So,
I got it in soft and medium,
because this one has more grip. When it rains
the disc sticks in the ground. And for another
type of terrain, when the terrain is with
a lot of dust or whatever, it doesn't skip away. This disc
falls to the ground and sticks. And the Deputy is
super understable.
I mean, you can do super long putts
and throw it with a little hyzer and this gets
straight and keep going. I mean, it's really cool. To me
I love this disc. It's one of my favorite discs.
Then the putters I throw: I have two,
one is an Aviar3 in Star, this one
I traded it to Fede for a disc and then I
I painted it pretty. It's cool, huh!
And then I also have a Vibram Ridge. And
the difference between the two is that this is
a lot more gummy. This putter, the Ridge,
it's from Vibram, that means, it's more rubbery. You can
throw it on the floor and it stays on the floor.
This skips a lot more. They are two stable putters
and I use them to make forehand approaches,
to make approach when you want to throw
high putter and come back, because you know
that this putter is coming back. I mean, it's the
two putters I use to throw away.
Well, moving on to the midrange. I have five
currently in the backpack. The first of them
is the Wolf. This disc is a Wolf in plastic
DX. In other words, the cheapest and most understable
of Innova and this disc, apart, has a -4
in turn, so you throw this disc straight out,
it wants to go to the right. This disc...
is very cool. I use it in holes where
maybe you have a hill that goes like this,
Well, you take, I mean, the hill goes down,
So you want if you throw away a disc.
and you're gonna go somewhere else, you can
take the disc, throw it flat and the disc alone
is gonna want to go to the right and avoid your throw
going up the hill. I use it for that type
of shots and also for shots in which
you are probably in a cornered place and
You don't know how to go out, you can throw it away.
flat and then it does... otherwise you can
throw it as forehand.
Then we have the Roc, also in plastic
DX. This disc is a little stable. In fact,
this used to fly... it was a little stable,
but since it's been breaking within the time
and since it's DX plastic, it's the cheapest.
and the most understable, so this disc
you can put on any line ant the
disc flies the way you want.
To make an anhyzer I take this midrange.
I mean, it's the disk I use to make anhyzer,
when I want to do hyzer too, but you don't
want it to go very far, because this
is not stable. I mean, this is very neutral. Well
this is a cool disc. It is one of the older
discs than I have in my backpack.
Then I also have two Compass, which are
two discs I just got myself lately.
One of them, the special edition of the
champion of Germany, also signed by
the champion of Germany, who is in our
club in Germany. These discs go super straight.
In other words, this disc, moreover, in plastic Opto,
I mean, good Latitude64 plastic, this is your disc.
you throw it away and it goes straight. I mean, this is my
disc to go straight. I've had it for a long time.
month or two and I'm super happy with the disc.
Well... and then the disc more... my most
stable midrange, that I also dyed it myself.
This is an MD4, which I bought
once for testing and since then
I do most of my midrange shots with it. I mean,
this is the midrange... that is, when you want to
make an approach and you have to go to the
end to the left, then... this one. Make a
forehand approach that you know is going to
go straight and then it's gonna come back... I mean, I'm
super happy with this midrange. So,
This midrange is the one I use for everything.
This is my favorite midrange.
Moving on to drivers. The most understable thing
I have is a "Manala", for people who
knows the English name: Underworld. This
they made it for me, there, Manala.
And this disc... is super understable. This
is absurd. This disc you throw it flat
and it is going roller. This disc I use it on
mostly, when you have to get out of some trouble,
How do I get out of here?
You have a tree in the middle that you have no way
to throw... And shoot flat and let the disc come back
alone. This is... I mean, Fede gave it to me
and I said, "Dude... What do I do with this?
What do I do with this? I don't know for
what I want it" and the truth is that I am
using more and more. I mean, it is super cool.
Well, this disk I have here is an Explorer,
that I bought it from the current German
Junior Champion, also signed by him.
This is a special edition of when he won
the German championship tournament. And
I'm trying it. I'm not
very convinced, but it's cool. It's
consistent. It does the same thing all the time. I don't know.
Maybe I'll keep it, maybe I won't. I don't
know, I'm not very convinced. Then I have
four other drivers. Two FD and two FD3. The
FD is a disc I once bought from the
guy that is currently the German champion,
which was previously sponsored by Discmania
and he told me he had the disks there gone astray,
because he switched to Latitude and didn't know what
do with them, and I saw them and I said, "Dude,
Bring them here, I'll buy them for you." All in all
I bought a bunch of discs. I bought him a
FD, an FD2 and an FD3. And I really liked the FD.
Right now I have two FD's on G-Star, which is
the plastic I like, or discmania G-Line,
which is the plastic that's cool to me because you
you can grab it with all
you strenght, besides, it's like that gummy. This
you can grab it with all your heart. And
of them is a gift from a friend. "Gotta
throw ém all!" And I this disc, well... it is
the disk that I also use for everything. This
Disk is is versatile. If you want to throw
hyzer, you put anhyzer, you throw it straight...
I do everything with this disc. I mean, this
is the wild card.
Well, and then going on to a driver a little bit
more stable: FD3 on C-line. This is the one that
I bought the champion of Germany, which I still
have. I don't like color at all,
because it gets lost super easy, I mean, it's the worst
color of the world for a disc, I think. Well...
yes, you can put more dark. And then I have
This. It is a gift from Fede: Doom Bird
2, super cool. They're both the same, only
that the doom bird is a little flatter and for me
it's better to throw a forehand.
I like it better to shoot from the right, and this
so I throw it backhand. But they are almost identical.
Well, and now we're getting to the distance drivers.
I have 5. Two different. Here I have three
Destroyers. One year I got crazy and
bought a lot of Destroyers, I think they were
5, one in each type of plastic and at the end
I end up using this three.
One I gave to Fede and the other I have at
home. That one I don't use it for anything.
One Metal Flake, which has a super cool color.
This is my favorite color. This is one color that you
can easily find.
And the other one that's on C-Line.
And these two discs is like
the FD, but they fly a little farther,
let's say. In other words, this disc is super versatile.
I make you an anhyzer, I make you
a flex, I make you a hyzer, I throw if for you straight... I mean,
I really do everything with this disc.
Or the vast majority of things. Then I have
the destroyer also in plastic G-Star,
which is a little more understable than the champion.
And what this disc has is that you can.
shoot flat and it will do all the flex.
I mean, this disc is really cool. This disc
It used to be like that and I wanted to paint it and I ruined it.
This disc is for loosing it.
It's very cool.
And then to finish I have two PD2, which are
two super overstable. I have one in
Blizzard and another in Swirly Star, which is
super cool. And these two discs are beasts,
so this is super overstable. This disc you can
throw flat and it will come back. And I use
it mainly to make skips, This
The disc is very cool and I use it a lot.
So, that's it. That's all I have with
me here and... See you next time!